噢 要修下楼梯
Ah- Fix that step.
-早上好 -人家还在睡觉呢
- Morning! - I'm still sleeping.
-结婚纪念日快乐 -嗯
- Happy anniversary. - Hmm.
-他们还说我们不能长久 -对呀
- And they said we wouldn't last. - Yeah.
-谁说的 -你看你 太萌了你
- Who said that? - Oh, look at you. You're cute.
-快点 打开看看 -你又搞啥了
- Go ahead. Open it. - What have you done?
没什么 没什么 没什么
Nothing. Something. Nothing.
-立体镜哇 -看看吧
- It's a View- Master. - Look inside.
是我们的相片
Oh, it's us.
看我们多年轻
Look at how young we are.
天啊 你那时候烫的头
Oh, God, that perm.
对啊 那发型衬托出了我的脸型
Yeah, it really framed my face.
怎么有个手镯的照片
Why is there a picture of a bracelet?
哈 有可能搞错了
Huh. Must be some kind of a mistake.
-是什么玩意儿啊 -菲尔 不会吧
- What the heck is that? - Phil, you didn't.
-你该不会 -有吗 有吗
- What did - Did he, did he?
噢 天啊
Oh, my God.
太漂亮了 亲爱的 我太喜欢了
It's beautiful. Oh, sweetie, I love it.
-好了 该看给你的礼物了 -该我啦 哪里
- Okay, your turn. - My turn? Where is it?
-梳妆柜上面 -哦
- It's on the bureau. - Oh.
我居然没看到
I'm surprised I didn't see it.
-在哪 -就那儿 红色信封
- Where? - It's there. The red envelope.
哦 就 贺卡吗
Oh. So - - card?
不 你猜错了
No. That's where you're wrong.
我开始亢奋了
I am so excited.
嘿 优惠券
Hey. Coupons for...
免费5次拥抱
five free hugs.
-不喜欢吗 -开玩笑 喜欢死了
- You don't like it? - Are you kidding me? I love it.
太有创意了 拥抱优惠券
It's so creative. Coupons for hugs,
其实本来就不要钱
which are usually free.
但是这样就看起来很正式 真心不错
But this makes it official, which is so great.
我很骄傲能想到如此绝妙的点子
I was so proud of myself when I thought of it...
因为完全不知道给你买什么
because you're impossible to buy for.
你从来就没有想要的东西
You never want anything.
那个...我想要的东西嘛
Um, things I want:
机器狗 夜视镜 吸虫器
Robot dog, night- vision goggles, bug vacuum,
GPS手表 石头样子的音箱
G.P.S. Watch, speakers that look like rocks.
我爱我老婆 但她送礼物太他妈没谱了
I love my wife, but she sucks at giving gifts.
不好意思我爆粗口了
I'm sorry for the pay- channel language,
但是 哦 酸奶机
but- Oh, yogurt maker.
一想到我喜欢的那些东西就抓狂
I can't not think of things I want.
我都不知道她什么时候需要换尿布
I can't tell if she needs a diaper change.
湿了就该换了呀
I'd think we'd be able to tell.
不 穿上这种尿布不好分辨
No, with these diapers, it's hard to tell.
-三重防漏 -专业防漏
- Triple leakage protection. - LeakLock.
特殊设计 呵护宝宝
Contours to protect her little body.
严丝合缝 绝无渗漏
No gapping or chapping.
小卡 你觉得我们是不是需要一晚
Cam, do you think that maybe we need a-
精彩夜生活 对
Night out. Yeah.
对 就是和一群成年人混几个小时
Yeah. Yes. Just a few hours with a couple of adults,
喝点酒 不谈宝宝
few drinks, no baby talk.
那会让我们成为更称职的家长
It'll make us better parents.
别诱惑我了 你的目的达到了
Stop drilling. You've struck oil.
我们把孩子交给歌洛莉亚照看 然后出去玩
We'll get Gloria to babysit. We're going out.
你沾了点口水
You got some spittle.
有吗 你觉得我们叫谁比较好
Do I? You know who'd be fun to call?
-萨尔 -萨尔
- Sal. - Sal.
来跳舞狂欢吧 莉莉 好耶
Ooh, raise the roof, Lily. Yeah.
我们要叫上萨尔
We're calling Sal.
萨尔绝对是我们在世上最好的朋友
Sal is our very best friend in the whole wide world.
我们那么爱她的原因嘛...
The reason we love her so much...
-就是她绝对放得开 -绝对的
- is she has absolutely no inhibitions. - No.
那还是在她喝酒之前
And that's before she starts drinking.
和她一起玩
Hanging out with her...
就像每天都是阿姆斯特丹周六狂欢夜
is like an Amsterdam Saturday night every day of the week.
讽刺的是
And, ironically,
萨尔被禁止进入阿姆斯特丹酒吧
Sal's not allowed back into Amsterdam.
哪天都不行
Any day of the week.
我们当然愿意照看宝宝
Of course we would love to have the baby.
她的表哥表姐们今天晚上都要来过夜
All the other cousins are sleeping over tonight.
人多才热闹
The more, the merrier.
好的 晚上见 拜拜
Okay, see you tonight. Bye- bye.
海莉还来不
Is Haley still coming?
你们是亲戚 再打她主意 我用水管喷你
You're related. I will spray you with the hose.
所有的孙儿门都
All the grandkids are
要来杰的夜间派对 算是家庭传统吧
coming over for Jay's Night. Family tradition.
每个人都得穿睡衣 那是他们的最爱
Everybody wears P.J.'s, which they love.
我做的炒牛肉"杰" 其实就是炒牛肉酱
I make my famous sloppy Jays, which are really sloppy joes...
但是是我杰做的 他们也喜欢
but made by Jay, which they love.
然后我们一起看一个西部电影
And then we all watch a Western together,
他们不喜欢没关系 因为今夜以杰为中心
which they don't really care for, but hey, it's Jay's Night.
妈 安德鲁·艾德勒家里晚上有派对
So, Mom, there's a party tonight at Andrew Adler's,
大家都要去
and everybody's gonna be there.
听起来不错 但是我有其他安排
Ooh, that sounds like so much fun, but I have other plans.
真有意思 但我指的是我要去
Oh, that's hi- larious. But I'm talking about me.
-真是"反常"啊 -亲爱的
- That's unusual. - Honey,
你说你今晚要去外公家
you said you'd go to your grandfather's tonight.
对啊 所以才刚刚好嘛
See, that's what's so perfect about this.
安德鲁家离外公家只有几个街区
Andrew only lives, like, a couple blocks away from Grandpa's.
我觉得我可以
So I figured that I could go-
亲爱的 你答应好了的
Sweetie, you made a commitment.
但是我真的想去嘛 还有每次我去外公那儿
But I really want to go. Plus, every time I go over to Grandpa's,
曼尼总是直勾勾地盯着我看
Manny just stares at me the whole time.
-可能如果你穿上胸罩 -艾丽克斯
- Maybe if you wore a bra- - Alex.
怎么了嘛 我迫不及待想去外公那里
What? I can't wait to go to Grandpa's.
-家人对我来说就是一切 -因为你没朋友
- Family means everything to me. - 'Cause you have no friends.
才不是 因为我爱外公
No. Because I love Grandpa.
他一天比一天老了
And he's getting older.
天知道他还能活多少年
Who knows how many years he has left?
-外公要死了吗 -他们没跟你说吗
- Is Grandpa dying? - Didn't they tell you?
艾丽克斯 不要折磨你弟弟了
Alex, stop torturing your brother.
不 你外公身体好得很
No. Your grandfather is fine.
现在而已
For now.
嗯 会是谁呢
Hmm. Who could that be?
你想到是某个特殊人物吗
You expecting someone special?
谢谢
Thank you.
-还送花呀 -对不起嘛
- Flowers too? - I'm sorry.
道什么歉啊 这花太漂亮了
Oh, what are you apologizing for? They're gorgeous.
有点过火 什么立体镜啊 手镯啊
That's too much. With the View- Master and the bracelet...
花啊 还有气球啊
and the flowers and the balloons-
-还有气球 -栓在你的汽车上
- Balloons? - They're attached to your car.
我只是不想让你因为
I just don't want you to feel bad...
只准备了优惠券 心存愧疚
about your little... coupons.
等等 你是不是
Wait a minute. You- You
觉得你的礼物只有优惠券
thought the coupons were your only present?
-开什么玩笑 -难道不是吗
- Are you kidding me? - They aren't?
当然不是 菲尔 拜托
No! Oh, Phil, come on.
是我们的结婚纪念日哎
It's our anniversary.
那些优惠券只不过是
Those coupons were just, like,
今天的前戏
a fun little way to kick off the day.
你真正的礼物晚上就到 你绝对会喜欢的
Your real present is coming tonight, and you're gonna love it.
绝对喜欢
Love it.
好耶
Cool.
我什么都没准备
I got nothing.
我完蛋了
I'm so screwed.
真是个充满回忆的地方
Oh, this place brings back so many memories.
-哦 天啊 -萨尔
- Oh, my God! - Sal!
起来 起来 快过来 熊抱抱
Get up! Get up! Get in here! Big bear!
小崽崽
Oh, my baby cub!
天啊 看看你
Oh, my God. Look at you.
哦 你们发现有什么不同了吗
Oh! You guys notice anything different?
是不是头发变长了
Your hair's longer, right?
-不是 -是不是洁牙了
- No. - Did you get your teeth bleached?
不不不 给你们点提示 波波波波大
No. Let me give you a little hint. Ba- boobs!
-天啊 -哇噢 叹为观止
- Oh, my God. - Oh, wow. Those are sensational.
对啊 你懂的 要感受一下吗
I know, right? You wanna touch 'em?
我虽是基佬 也懂捏乳之妙 你没意见吧
I'm gay, not dead. Are you okay with this?
好啊 你百香果代基里酒喝多了
Yeah. You're drinking a passion- fruit daiquiri.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
-行了 快来吧 -抓奶龙爪手
- Okay, get in there. - I'm coming in.
莉莉喜欢 那歌声吗
So, Lily likes that, that... singing?
-是的 那能让她放松 -好吧
- Yes. It relaxes her. - Oh, okay.
莉莉肯定是聋子
So Lily's deaf.
小捣蛋们来了
There are my little stinkers.
-嗨 -外公好
- Howdy. - Hi, Grandpa.
-进来 -嘿
- Come on in. - Hey.
-哈罗 -哈罗哈罗
- Hola. - Hola, hola.
你好呀 海莉
Well, hello there, Haley.
消停消停吧 小色鬼
Take it down a notch, Jethro.
准备好疯玩了吗
So, you guys ready for some fun?
干嘛
What?
我爱你 外公 你永远活在我的心中
I love you, grandpa, and I'm never gonna forget you.
好了好了 快松开 小家伙
Okay, okay. Back at ya, champ.
喔喔 今天可是睡衣派对 你们的睡衣呢
Whoa, whoa, whoa. This is a pajama party. Where's your P.J.'s?
在我包里面 我得跟你说件事
Yeah, they're in my bag. I need to talk to you about something.
她想和迪兰去参加派对 外公
She wants to go to a party with Dylan, grandpa
艾丽克斯 闭嘴
Shut up, Alex.
在我朋友安德鲁·艾德勒家里
It's at my friend Andrew Adler's.
离这里只有几个街区
He lives three blocks from here.
-只有几步路 -对呀
- Oh. Walking distance. - Right.
我其实不好意思开口的
So I wouldn't ask you this,
因为我喜欢来你这儿
because I love coming to your house,
但是这次派对很重要 我
but it's kind of an important party, and I-
别人请你去他家
Somebody invites you over,
你总不能让人家难堪
the last thing you wanna do is insult them.
-就是说呀 -很高兴我们达成了一致
- Exactly. - I'm glad we agree.
哦天啊 那么容易 太爽了
Oh, my God. That was so easy. This is awesome.
你是真不明白刚刚是怎么回事吧
You really don't understand what just happened there, do you?
-海莉 换上睡衣 -什么
- P.J.'s on, Haley! - What?
我自愿提供我的卧室让她换衣服
Um, I would be happy to let her change in my room.
会是谁呢 是你期待的某个特殊人物吗
Who could that be? Are you expecting someone special?
你干了什么
What did you do?
没什么啊 我只知道门口有个人
Nothing. I just know that there's someone at the door.
摇滚吧 菲尔·邓菲
Rock on, Phil Dunphy.
嘭 感动落泪吧你 菲尔
Bam! Read it and weep, Phil.
-哦 -是伊茨啊
- Oh. - It's the Iz.
-谁 -斯班道芭蕾乐队的伊茨·拉法提啊
- Who? - Izzy LaFontaine from Spandau Ballet.
来自"死怕"什么的"迪茨·荡铁"耶
Dizzy Dontaine from Spa, Hey.
他反应过来了
He's got it now.
-他反应过来了 只是有点懵 -没错
- He's got it. He's just seriously freaking out. - Yes!
菲尔爱死斯班道芭蕾了
Phil loves Spandau Ballet.
我们第一次接吻 车上放的歌就是《真实》
That song "True" was playing in the car the first time we kissed.
那是我们的定情之歌 所以我谷歌了一下
It's our song. So I did some research,
发现主吉他手就住在
found out that the lead guitarist lives,
离这里大概40英里外的地方
like, 40 miles from here.
电话簿里就有他电话
He was in the phone book.
仿佛回到了80年代
How '80s is that?
我从来没喜欢过斯班道芭蕾
I never liked Spandau Ballet.
在我们的婚姻史上
Our entire marriage,
我就没提到过斯班道芭蕾
I never once mentioned Spandau Ballet.
我甚至连名字都念得不对吧
Am I even pronouncing that right?
今天来给我们开私人演唱会的是吉他手
Here to play a private concert for us is the guitarist-
-是贝司手 -兼主唱
- Bass player, actually. - And lead singer-
-是伴唱 伴唱 -斯班道芭蕾的
- Well, backup, backup. - Of Spandau Ballet.
在理查德·米勒和马丁·坎普之间
Between Richard Miller and Martin Kemp.
哦 是他们呀
Oh, those guys.
-我想死你们了 -哦
- I miss you two guys so much. - Oh.
-想死了 敬我们 -好的
- So, so much. To us. - Yeah.
-敬我们 -敬我们 三个火枪手
- To us. - To us, the Three Musketeers.
-卡波 -什么
- Cabo! - What?
不是吧混蛋 我们谈了很多次了
Seriously, you bastards. We've been talking about it forever.
说定了 我们要去卡波 快点快点
We're doing it. We're going to Cabo. Let's do it. Let's do it.
好吧 我们去
All right. Let's go.
行啊行啊 肯定会很有趣的
Yeah. Yes. Yes. That would be fun.
只是有趣吗 开玩笑
Fun? Are you joking?
玛格丽特酒 加上你们 以及我的波波
Margaritas, you guys, these guys.
肯定会终身难忘的
It's gonna be epic.
但是我们得找人照看下莉莉
Yeah, but we need to find someone for Lily.
好的好的
Okay, okay. Um,
我过去和女招待调情 你们给我多少钱
how much are you gonna pay me to go make out with the waitress?
好吧 等等 是哪一个
All right. Now, wait. Which one?
年轻的还是年老的
The old one or the young one?
年轻的10美元 年老的20
Ten for the young one, 20 for the old.
30块钱都归我了
I am about to make 30 bucks.
-我得问问莉莉的情况 -现在吗
- I'm just gonna go check on Lily real quick. - Right now?
-对 马上就好 -但是我要
- Yeah. It'll just take a second. - Well, I'm just-
你们会错过我和黛西小姐调情的
you're gonna miss me sluttin' it up with Driving Miss Daisy.
-就一小下 -很快的
- It'll just take a second. - Real fast.
你们应该"弄死"宝宝
You should kill that baby.
-什么 -你们应该"联系"宝宝
- What? - You should call the baby.
我爱死你们了
I love you guys so much.
-她是不是说 -我怕怕
- Did she just- - I'm scared.
-没好牌了 -我想我有一对好牌
- I got nothing. - I think I have a very good pair.
-你胸前那对是好牌 亲爱的 -我也弃牌了
- You sure do, honey. - And I got squat.
我也没什么好牌
I don't think I have anything either.
你开玩笑呢 那是顺子
Are you kidding me? That's a straight.
-真的吗 -她赢了
- Really? - She wins.
你赢了
You won.
-我赢了 -真棒 海莉
- I win. - You got it, Haley.
好吧 我觉得该奖励自己一听汽水
You know what? I think I deserve a soda.
-干得好 海莉 -你看见了吗
- Good job, Haley. - Did you see that?
-她还说不会玩呢 -她都不知道自己赢牌了
- "I don't know how to play." - She didn't even know.
她应得的
You know, she deserves it.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, honey.
-老天 你吓坏我了 -你怎么
- Gee, you scared me. - How did you-
灯灭了 要是不马上换
Lightbulb went out. You don't change these right away,
回头就懒的换了
you never get around to it.
好了
There.
现在周围的一切"状况" 我看得一清二楚
Now I can see everything that goes on around here.
我很有这方面的经验
I've had a little practice at this.
海莉的小花招我全部见识过
Haley wasn't throwing anything at me I hadn't seen before
她妈妈和某人当年都耍过
from her mother and then some.
可惜没人能逃得出我的手掌
But nobody gets off The Rock.
好了 这首歌 在美国不怎么流行
Right. Here's a track. Wasn't so popular in America.
但在荷兰登上过排行榜的第六名
Got to number six on the Netherlands charts though.
那整个夏天 我在阿姆斯特丹简直寸步难行
That whole summer I couldn't walk to the corner in Amsterdam
到处都是女歌迷围上来
without mobs of birds coming up
热情地要和我共饮泡泡鸡尾酒
and asking me for the double bubble.
好的 快开始吧
Okay, just play it, I think. Yeah.
他 他太棒了 亲爱的
He's- He's awesome, honey.
不客气
You're welcome.
*今夜*
*Tonight*
*良宵*
*So right*
*爱人*
*Lover*
菲尔 你的爱人在等你的吻呢
Hey, Phil, I think your lover wants a kiss from you.
好的
Oh. Okay.
拜托 老兄 别像亲吻妹妹那样
Oh, come on, man. She's not your sister.
快深情长吻一个
Give her a proper snog.
你没事吧
You all right?
刚刚那玩笑开得不好 不好笑
That's a bad joke. Not funny.
我妹妹因为糖尿病并发症失去了一条腿
My sister lost her feet to complications from diabetes.
我给你倒杯水吧 伙计
Okay. Can I get you some water there, guy, or-
-是啊 -有茶吗
- Yeah. - You got tea?
-有的 我去倒 -要甘菊的
- Yes, of course. I'll get that. - Chamomile.
-你好好享受就行 -好的
- You don't miss a minute. - Okay.
老天 怎么 瞧瞧我做了什么
Oh, God. Why did- You know, look at what I'm doing.
-我把自己弄成主角了 真是扫兴 -没有
- I'm- I'm making it all about me. What a downer. - No.
-今晚的主角是你 让今夜此生难忘吧 -没没
- It's your evening. Let's make it great, man. - No.
说几个曲子吧 我全部照唱
Name your playlist. I'll do it all.
就经典曲目吧
Oh, um, just the classics.
-几首出名的 -那是肯定的
- Let's play the hits. - We'll get to the hits, obviously.
就说旧专辑的曲目吧 B面最喜欢哪首
Go to the back catalog, man. Favorite B- side.
有意思 只不过我最记不住歌名了
That's fun. Yeah, that's fun. Uh, just- I'm so bad with titles.
哼来听听
Hum it.
-*今夜* -那是我刚才弹的那首 对吧
- *Tonight* - I just did that one, didn't I? Yeah.
所以才在我脑海里回旋 那这首
That's why it's in the noodle. So I guess-
-是哪张专辑里的 -第二张 好像是第二张
- No. What album is that on? - Second. I wanna say second.
封面是什么
What's on the cover?
有个巫师 要么就是海景画
There's a warlock, I think, or a seascape.
巫师 噢 《千年日出》
Warlock. Oh. Millennium Sunrise.
就是《千年日出》
Millennium Sunrise.
没有《千年日出》这张专辑
There is no Millennium Sunrise record.
怎么 你根本就不是粉丝
What- What? You're not a Fandau.
刚刚在门口 你都不知道我是谁
You didn't even know who I was at the door.
我看你的眼神就知道
I saw it in your eyes.
别告诉克莱尔
Please don't say anything to Claire.
-她弄错了 -我是被耍了吗
- She made a mistake. - Am I being punk'd?
此事对她太重要了 我不想伤害她的感情
This means so much to her, and I don't wanna hurt her feelings.
她的感情 那我的感情呢
Her feelings? Well, what about my feelings?
这是我的事业啊 老兄
This is my career, man.
我的音乐曾是人们的最爱
You know, my music was the soundtrack to people's lives.
现在却一文不值了 你觉得这是什么感觉
Now I'm nothing. How do you think that feels?
真是太侮辱人了
This is really humiliating.
别别别 别走别走
No, no, no. Don't go. Don't go.
嘿 你俩干嘛呢
Hey. What are you guys doing?
他允许我摸这把吉他
He let me touch it!
她说了"弄死" 真的
Yeah, I think she said "kill," Cam. I do.
也许是开玩笑的 她一直都挺黑色幽默的
Maybe it was just a joke. She's always had a dark sense of humor.
那倒是 还记得她的万圣节装束吗
That's true. Remember her Halloween costume?
她扮成齐格弗里德和罗伊的结合体
When she came as Siegfried and part of Roy.
-才不久的事情 -对对 就是个玩笑
- It was too soon. - Yeah. Yeah. This was just a joke.
对 好了她来了
Yes. Yeah. Here she comes.
这样吧 我提一下莉莉 看她什么反应
Look, I'm gonna bring up Lily. We'll see what she says.
-给她看点照片 -付钱吧 小妞们
- Show her some pictures. - Pay up, bitches.
又端酒过来了
Whoa. More drinks.
免费的哟
Free drinks.
-萨尔 你得看看这些照片 -是什么
- Sal, you've got to look at these pictures. - What are they?
-莉莉在动物园 -真可爱
- It's Lily at the zoo. - Oh, cute.
-看这张 -萌死了萌翻了萌得要流泪
- Look at that one. - Cute! Cute. Cutie, cutie, cute, et cetera.
你们得带莉莉去卡波
So you guys are gonna have to bring Lily to Cabo,
反正你们走哪儿都带着她
now that you're the guys that always bring Lily?
-这个嘛 -行吧
- Well, you know- - Yeah, probably.
-我要把她丢进大海里 -什么
- I will throw her in the ocean. - What?
我说我要去尿尿了
I said I gotta go pee.
-行了 这回不是我们听错了 -绝对不是
- Okay, that wasn't even close. - Nope.
怎么办 要说点什么吗
I mean, what do we do? Do we say something?
怎么提这事啊
How do we even bring it up?
她威胁我们的宝宝 你担心的竟是开场白
She threatened our child, and that's your concern- a segue?
-你知道是怎么回事吗 -什么
- You know what this is? - What?
-头生子综合征 -什么玩意儿
- This is first- child syndrome. - What?
就是头生子原本非常幸福快乐
It's where the first child is happy,
第二个宝宝出生以后
and then the second child comes along,
头生子就开始嫉妒小宝宝
and the first child gets jealous of the second child
然后闹脾气
and starts acting out.
是啊 忒有道理了 可萨尔不是我们的孩子
Yes. That's brilliant, except Sal's not our child, so-
想想看啊 我们曾经那么照顾她
Think about it. Listen, we've practically done everything for her.
她流泪时 我们给她温暖的怀抱
We've held her when she's cried.
她无法走路时 我们背着她
We've carried her when she couldn't walk.
-就差没教她如何蹲马桶撒尿了 -伙计们
- We've done everything but potty- train her. - Um- Hey, guys.
-我在想 -不好意思
- I was thinking- Oh. - Oh. Sorry.
我们去卡波的时候
When we go to Cabo,
要找个带池滨酒吧的酒店
we have to find a hotel with a swim- up bar,
来来回回地跑厕所 太他妈傻逼了
'cause this going back and forth to the bathroom is a fool's game.
-行 继续喝吧 -萨尔 我们得谈谈
- Okay, let's get more drinks. - Sal, we got to talk.
-是关于莉莉的 -噢 我就知道
- It's about Lily. - Oh, shocker.
-好吧 -你觉得有没有可能
- Okay. - Do you think it's at all possible...
也许你有那么一丁点嫉妒她
that maybe- maybe you're jealous of her?
-什么 说毛呢 -只是
- What? What? - It's just-
-我也不确定 -我不 你干嘛这么问
- I don't know. - I don't- Where- Why would you say that?
因为你拒绝看她的照片
Well, because you won't look at any pictures of her...
还说要弄死她 要把她丢进大海什么的
and you talked about killing her and throwing her in the ocean.
那完全是玩笑嘛 拜托
Okay, that was a joke, you guys. Come on.
好吧 把小野洋子的照片拿来瞧瞧
Fine. Show me the pictures of Yoko.
听听...
See, it's...
玩笑来着 别这样啊
It's a joke. You guys! Come on.
她是亚洲人嘛 还拆散了我们的小团体
'Cause she's Asian, and she broke up our group.
我...只是 听着 我们得承认
I- I just- Look, let's at least
我们的关系和从前不太一样了
acknowledge that things have changed between us.
你得明白
And you know what?
莉莉的出现 不会使我们对你的爱减少丝毫
Because Lily's here doesn't mean we love you any less.
-绝对不会 -到底怎么了
- No. Absolutely not. - What's wrong?
我们以前那么亲密
We used to be really close, and
你们没事就给我打电话 现在你们压根不给我打了
you used to call me a lot. And now you never call me.
-但是我们 -不
- Well, but we- - No.
上周我做了个噩梦
And last week I had a really bad dream,
我就在想 "我要给他们打电话"
and I was thinking, "Okay, I'm gonna call them."
然后我就觉得 "不行 不能打给他们
And then I thought, "Oh, no, you can't call them...
把小宝宝吵醒了怎么办啊"
because you might wake up their baby."
-我们随时欢迎你的来电 -随时欢迎 亲爱的
- You can always call. - Oh, honey, always call us.
别这样 真抱歉当时没有陪着你
No. I'm sorry we haven't been there.
但现在我们在你身边呢
We're here now, okay?
好啦
Okay?
-好点了吗 -我觉得你沾上了
- Feel better? - I think you just put a little-
口水吗
Spittle?
她睡着了吗
Did she just fall asleep?
真希望莉莉也能这么容易入睡
I wish Lily would fall asleep like that.
给她8杯龙舌兰就行了
Give her eight shots of tequila.
我真不明白她怎么就不睡觉呢
I don't understand why she's not falling asleep.
-我知道原因 -电影来啦
- I have a theory. - I got the movie.
曼尼 去弄点爆米花吧
Manny, why don't you go fire up some popcorn?
你在找这个吗
You looking for these?
-你偷走了我的鞋 -不 我剥夺了你的自由
- You took my shoes? - No, I took your freedom.
抱歉 孩子 今晚不是属于你的
Sorry, kid. It ain't your night.
你为什么要这样
Why are you being like this?
我只想去那个派对 也就两小时
I just wanted to go to that party for, like, two hours.
本来这会儿都回来了 你同意一下会死吗
I would've been back by now. Would that have killed you?
真是虎母无犬女
She's just like her mother.
你干嘛这么折磨海莉
Why are you treating Haley like this?
我 是她在耍性子吧
Me? She's the one acting like a pill.
她并非是刻意跟你唱对台戏
You're taking this too personally.
我在海莉那么大的时候 也很爱自己的外公
When I was Haley's age, I loved my grandfather,
但同样很爱去派对和男孩子们玩
but I still wanted to go to parties and be with boys.
我懂我懂 克莱尔也一样 还有米奇尔
I know. I know. So did Claire... and Mitchell.
但是你知道吗
But you know what?
你要是跟我对着干 绝对没有好果子吃
You try to put something over on me, you're gonna lose.
是怎样 你要把这事儿闹大吗
So, what? Now you're gonna make this into a big game?
我只是想多和他们共处 仅此而已
I'm trying to keep 'em around a little bit longer, that's all.
天知道我还有多少个这样的夜晚了
I mean, who knows how many nights like this I got left?
-我已经开始想你了 -这孩子今天有毛病吗
- I miss you already. - What's wrong with this kid tonight?
去厨房给大家帮忙 我就来
Go in the kitchen and help out the guys, and I'll be right in.
你想多和外孙女在一起是好事
It's great that you wanna spend time with your granddaughter,
但真的要以这种方式吗
but is this really the way?
-好吧 -你是个好外公
- Fine. - You're a good abuelo.
-她在楼上 -我知道
- She's upstairs. - I know.
迪兰
Dylan!
-什么 -出来吧
- Yeah? - Get up.
你是来找海莉去派对的吧
You're here to take Haley to the party, right?
-是啊 -她在屋里呢
- Yeah. - She's in the house.
你怎么知道我在这儿
How did you know I was here?
我第一次见菲尔就是在那儿
This is how I first met Phil.
多谢了 外公 我们11点就回来
Thanks again, Grandpa. We'll be back by 11:00.
-我会去找你的 -我想也是
- I will track you down. - I believe that.
-那是什么味道 -炒牛肉"杰" 去尝尝吧
- What's that smell? - Sloppy jays. Help yourself.
还剩好多呢
There's plenty left.
噢 炒牛肉"杰"是因为你叫杰
Oh. Sloppy jays because your name's Jay.
谐音很正
Right on.
真不敢相信她喜欢这种脑残货
Can't believe she's into this guy.
要不我给你来一盘
If you want, I'll fix you a plate.
-好的 太好了 -不去派对了吗
- Yeah, definitely. That'd be great. - But what about the party?
我们就走 就...
We can go in just a minute. Just let-
不是吧 是《枪战》 我特喜欢这电影
Oh, no way. The Gunfighter. I love this movie.
迪兰 派对
Dylan, the party.
但是...是牛仔哎
Oh. But... cowboys.
别抗争了 海莉 男人永远都是孩子
Don't fight it, Haley. They never grow up.
-谢谢 -我去厨房拿杯咖啡
- Thanks. - I'm going to the kitchen for an espresso.
-有人需要什么吗 -不了谢谢
- Anybody need anything? - No, thanks.
好了
Okay.
二 三 四
Two, three, four.
当时正值1991年
The year was 1991.
美国沉浸于"沙漠风暴"行动中
America was immersed in Desert Storm.
与此同时 在国内 另一股风暴正袭来
Meanwhile, stateside, another storm was brewing...
向我心中袭来
in my heart.
-太蠢了 对吧 -不
- This is stupid, isn't it? This is- - No.
-很傻吗 菲尔 -不不 请继续 克莱尔
- Is it stupid, Phil? - No. Just keep- keep going, Claire.
-非常有情调 -好的
- It's wonderful. - Okay.
在弗里特利餐厅共享晚餐后
After a romantic dinner at Fratelli's,
羞涩的情侣为对方献上了初吻
a certain nervous young couple shared their first kiss...
而广播里正是这首歌
as the radio played this song.
*太真实*
*So true*
*似乎滑稽可笑*
*Funny how it seems *
*时机恰好*
*Always in time*
*美梦却总不能成真*
*But never in line for dreams*
*四脚相对 深深相爱*
*Head over heels when toe to toe*
*那声音是*
*This is the sound of-*
算了 不行 抱歉 我办不到
You know what? No. No. Sorry. Sorry. Not gonna do it.
怎么了
What's wrong?
-出什么事了 -你知道这首歌的名字吗
- What's going on? - Do you even know the name of this song?
-"破" -《真实》
- P- "True."
-《真实》 -《真实》
- "True." - "True."
他是假装的 瞧出来了吗
Right. This is false. See?
我不会为"假人"演奏"真实"
I'm not gonna play "True" for someone who's false.
他甚至根本不知道我们乐队
See, he doesn't- He doesn't even know the band.
-更不是粉丝 -他知道这个乐队
- He's not a fan, a Fandau. - Yes, he does know the band.
他当然知道啊 这是我们的定情之歌
Of course he does. 'Cause this is our song.
你爱这首歌 快和他说
You love this song. Tell him this is our song.
-对 你说啊 菲尔 -这不是我们的定情之歌
- Right. Tell him, Phil. - It's not our song, Claire.
我们的歌是
Our song is
"黑暗中的管弦乐"乐队的《如果你离开》
"If You Leave" by Orchestral Manoeuvres in the Dark.
-该死! -你确定吗
-OH! - Are you sure?
非常确定 我在我们的婚礼上唱过
Pretty sure. I sang it at our wedding.
噢 我真是个蠢货
Oh, I'm an idiot.
实际上 他才是蠢货
Well, actually, he's the idiot.
那可是首分手歌
He fell in love to a break- up song.
别理他 今晚多美好啊
Ignore him. This is beautiful.
-我很喜欢 -我不喜欢
- I love it. - I hate this. I hate this.
你如此温柔贴心 我却不能给你
You're so sweet and nice, and I can't even give you...
一份像样的周年纪念礼物
a decent anniversary present.
我太爱你了 但我觉得你可能永远不会知道
I love you so much, and I feel you just are never gonna know it.
-我知道 我知道 -你真的知道吗
- I know it. I know it. - You do know it?
-当然了 -真的吗
- Yes. - You do?
这个礼物多好啊
And this is an awesome gift.
-知道为什么吗 -为什么
- You know why? - Why?
-我们有新歌了 -好吧
- You just gave us a new song. - Okay.
让你们又黏糊起来了是吧
Sort of brought you back together, eh?
-算是吧 -差不多
- Seems. - Sort of.
-"爱火重燃" -好的
- Rekindled fires of a dying passion? - Sure.
给低劣的谎言照射一丝希望的曙光
Shot a ray of hope into this gloomy suburban lie?
-别废话了 哥们 -快演奏吧 伊茨
- All right, buddy. - Just play it, lzzy.
献给克莱尔
For you, Claire.
*我知道*
*I know this*
*爱很真实*
*Much is true*
*我知道*
*I know this*
*爱很真实*
*Much is true*
-她太可爱了 -可不是嘛
- She is so sweet. - Isn't she?
像个小天使
Like a little angel.
让我抱抱她
Let me hold her.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.